mdedge.com 2002-12-09

# MDEdge.com - Physician Community

At MD _Edge_ , we understand that privacy is an important and necessary part of the medical profession. We want you to know that we take your privacy just as seriously as you would take the privacy of your patients. The MD _Edge_ Web site is a physician-only community, and MD _Edge_ is committed to honoring your privacy and earning your trust. To that end, we have adopted a set of standards and special protections for dealing with your personal information. This document is our privacy policy; it outlines why we collect and how we handle your personal information.

 **Coverage**  
This privacy policy relates to our Web site, (www.mdedge.com). "MD _Edge_ " is also the name used to refer to our company as a whole.

When we refer to ourselves as "we" or "MD _Edge_ ," we mean our entire company, including any company that we control (for example, a subsidiary that we own). We may share information among those companies that we own or control, but that information is always protected under the terms of this privacy policy.

You should read the privacy policy of any Web site that you visit after you leave our site. We are not responsible for how other Web sites treat your information, which they may collect, or privacy.

 **Information Collection**  
MD _Edge_ is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. MD _Edge_ collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

 **Information Collected from Unregistered Visitors**  
Visitors to the MD _Edge_ Web site can access the Web site's log in page, and browse some areas of the site, without disclosing any personal information. As a visitor, we do track information provided to us by your browser, including the Web site you came from (the "referring URL"), the type of Web browser you use, when you accessed our Web site, and other information that does not identify you personally.

 **Registration**  
In order to use this Web site, a physician-user must first complete a registration process. When you register to use MD _Edge_ , we ask you to provide us with certain personal and other information, including, but not limited to, your name, address, e-mail address, and DEA number. This identifying information is required for registration. We use this information to positively identify you as an individual and to verify that you are a physician.

During the registration process, you will also generate a personal profile, including information about your medical specialty, content preferences, and notification preferences. We use this information as the basis for the highly defined personalization provided by MD _Edge_. It helps us to determine the types of information and services that are most likely to interest you and to direct this information to you. You may change your registration information at any time by accessing the "My Profile" area from your personal home page on the Web site.

 **Identifying Information from Other Sources**  
We may also collect information about physicians who register on our Web site from other sources in order to verify their licensure status and identity. In some cases, we will also collect identifying information from a third party in order to offer special content or opportunities to a specified individual or group of users. All user information received from other sources is handled by MD _Edge_ in accordance with this privacy policy.

 **Other Information Collected**  
Revenue Opportunities: MD _Edge_ offers unique revenue opportunities to physician-users such as consulting engagements and market research studies. In most cases, these opportunities include an honorarium payable to participants. Some of the opportunities are offered and compensated directly by us, and some opportunities are offered through our Web site by affiliates or partner companies. If you decide to participate in revenue opportunities offered through MD _Edge_ , you may be asked to confirm existing personal information or to provide additional information, such as your Social Security number or Federal Tax ID number, in order to receive your honorarium. Once you participate in a revenue opportunity, the information you provide will be saved by MD _Edge_. Please note, as well, that if a revenue opportunity which you select is offered by another company, MD _Edge_ may provide necessary identifying or payment information to that company to facilitate your participation and eventual payment.

Discussion Boards and Commentary: MD _Edge_ provides opportunities for feedback and interaction by physician-users in the form of discussion boards and commentary submissions within the Web site. When you post a message on our Web site, that message will be accompanied by identifying information that will become public, and that all registered users will see. MD _Edge_ reserves the right to determine what identifying information will be displayed along with a message, and this information may include your initials, geographical location, specialty, or other such information. Please remember, when you are posting publicly, any user of our Web site can see your message. You should not post any information you want to keep private to any public forum on our Web site. 

Additional Forms and E-mails: We may also ask you to provide additional information via e-mail or Web-based forms in order to obtain additional services or information or to resolve complaints or concerns. This additional information will be subject to the terms of this privacy policy.

 **Cookies**  
Cookies are a technology used by MD _Edge_ to identify a user as the user moves through our Web site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a user's hard drive containing information about the user. We use cookies to personalize our Web site and to track your usage of the site. Cookies can save you time and improve your experience on MD _Edge_. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, you would not have to log in a password more than once while you are on the site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target your interests to enhance your experience on our site. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.

Your Web browser can be set to allow you to control whether you will accept cookies, reject cookies, or to notify you each time a cookie is sent to you. If your browser is set to reject cookies, our Web site will not recognize you when you return, and significant functionality may be lost. The Help section of your browser will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting cookies. We strongly recommend that you set your browser to allow cookies if you plan to use our Web site.

Although cookies do not normally contain personally identifiable information, if you are a registered user we may associate your registration information with cookies our Web site places on your computer's hard drive. Associating a cookie with your registration data allows us to offer increased personalization and functionality. For example, you can activate the "auto log in" feature of the Web site, and it will remember your user name and password in order to bypass the sign-in process when you return to the site. Without cookies, this functionality would not be possible. For more information about the "auto log in" feature, we strongly recommend that you read the auto log in help file found on the log in page and in the registration process.

 **Log Files**  
We also gather information about you that is automatically collected by our Web server, such as your IP address and domain name. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

**Policy on Children's Privacy**  
The MD _Edge_ Web site is designed and intended for use by adults, and is not intended to be - and may not be - used by children under the age of 18. Minors under the age of 18 may not register for our Web site, and we do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we know is under the age of 18.

 **Use of Information**  
This section outlines our policies regarding the use of information that we collect through our Web site and from other sources.

 **Aggregate Data**  
We gather aggregate data about users through the registration process and through Web site usage. We use this data for product development and improvement activities. We also use it to help us to understand the quality and impact of various content and other offerings within our Web site and for market analysis. We may provide information from our Web site in aggregate form, with identifying information removed, to third parties. For example, we may share with a partner company information regarding viewership of a particular piece of content or participation in a particular offering on the Web site, without disclosing the identities of the users involved.

Any third party that receives aggregated information from us must agree to the terms of our privacy policy and must agree not to attempt to re-identify the people reflected in the data. Depending on our agreement with the third parties, we may or may not charge for this information. 

**Restricted Data Sharing with Third Parties**  
In addition to aggregate information, we reserve the right to share some kinds of information with third parties. When we share information with third parties, we ask that they agree in writing to abide by our privacy policy. If we discover that a third party inadvertently disclosed personal information about any of our users, we will take immediate action to prevent further occurrences. Other than the cases described below, we will not release personally identifiable information to a third party without your consent. Also, if we ask your consent to release personal information to a third party, we will use our best efforts to clearly define and limit the scope of your consent.

Individuals and Companies Who Work for Us: We contract with other entities to provide many of the services required to operate our Web site. For example, we have an outside vendor for customer service and we host our Web site with a third-party co-location and Web hosting service for security and reliability. In addition, we may validate your licensure status and other information against available databases that list licensed physicians. These other companies may have limited access to some of the personal information we maintain about our users. They must have this information to perform their respective services. We require all of these companies to abide by the terms of our privacy policy, to limit their information access to the minimum necessary to perform their services, and not to use the information they may access for purposes other than fulfilling their services to MD _Edge_. In addition, all employees of MD _Edge_ are bound by proprietary information and non-disclosure agreements that prevent them from using any data possessed by MD _Edge_ in any way.

Revenue Opportunities: Some revenue opportunities (consulting engagements, market research, etc.) offered on our Web site are provided by other companies. In these cases, the provider of the opportunity may ask you for specific personal or identifying information required for your participation. The party directly collecting the information will be clearly indicated. In addition, in order for you to participate in these revenue opportunities and to receive compensation for your participation, it may be necessary for MD _Edge_ to supplement the information that the provider requests from you with other identifying information from your MD _Edge_ user profile. Please note that while we require all of these companies to abide by the terms of our privacy policy, MD _Edge_ cannot be held responsible for the use of your personal information by any third party.

Promotional Offers and Special Opportunities: Sometimes we offer special content or opportunities to a specified individual or group of users on behalf of a partner or other company. When we do this, we do not give that business names and addresses of our users. We provide a variety of mechanisms for you to tell us you do not want to receive such promotional offers. 

Legal Requirements: If we believe that the release of any information is required to comply with law or is required by an order of a court of law, we may release account and other personal information as required. 

**Links**  
This Web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

**Referral**  
If you elect to use our referral service for informing a colleague about MD _Edge_ , we will ask you for the friend's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the Web site. MD _Edge_ stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. 

**Security and Protection of Information**  
MD _Edge_ has taken a number of security measures to protect information that we have collected about you. 

When you submit sensitive information via the Web site, your information is protected both online and off-line. When you submit information to MD _Edge_ via the Web site, that information is encrypted and is protected with an Internet security protocol know as Secure Sockets Layer - SSL. While on a secure page, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers displays as locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing the Web'. 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also take reasonable steps that we determine are important to protect user information off-line. There is restricted access to all of our users' information. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. Employees must enter their password to gain access to your information. Furthermore, all employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Our employees are notified and/or reminded frequently about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure Web-hosting environment, in a locked cage. 

**Your Access to Information and Notification Choices**  
Here we share with you how to access and correct information we have about you, and how to select communication preferences for this Web site.

 **Correction of Information**  
You can access your personal information at any time by clicking on the 'My Profile' link from your home page on the MD _Edge_ Web site. If you believe that information collected by our Web site is in error, you may edit your personal profile any time that you like. 

You may also ask that the personal information you have given to us be deleted from our Web site. Requests for deletion of your information will result in termination of your access to the MD _Edge_ Web site. In these situations, we may keep certain non-personally identifiable demographic information about you for internal purposes. You may contact MD _Edge_ customer support (support@mdedge.com) at any time to make changes to your personal information or to remove your personal information from the Web site. 

**Getting a Written Copy of Your Profile**  
You can get a copy of your personal profile information by printing a copy of the page containing the information from your Web browser.

 **Notification Choices**  
MD _Edge_ conducts five different types of e-mail communication to its users based upon the e-mail address you provide during registration. 

Service Updates: We send users service announcement updates via e-mail. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the Web site.

Newsletter: The MD _Edge_ newsletter is an opt-in service which is provided up to twice per month, which means that you must request to receive newsletter mailings from us.

Breaking News: Breaking news is also an opt-in service which is provided irregularly (only when such news is available). You must request to receive breaking news mailings from us.

Content Updates: This opt-in service will provide you e-mail communication up to once per week to notify you of content added to the Web site that matches your personal profile. You must opt-in to receive content update mailings from us.

Opportunity Updates: This service is also opt-in and provides information regarding new or ongoing opportunities available on the MD _Edge_ Web site that match your user profile. Please remember that such opportunities will be filled by qualified physician users on a first come, first served basis.

You can change your notification preferences at any time to control what e-mail communications you receive from MD _Edge_. Notification preferences can be changed by accessing the 'My Profile' link from your personal home page on the MD _Edge_ Web site or by e-mailing [support@mdedge.com](mailto:support@mdedge.com).

 **Changes and Revisions to this Privacy Policy**  
MD _Edge_ reserves the right to change this privacy policy at any time by posting a new privacy policy at this location. As our privacy policy changes in significant ways, we will make every reasonable effort to notify you of the changes. Any change made to this policy will be reflected within the Privacy Policy link on the MD _Edge_ Web site in a timely manner and will be effective upon such posting on our site. It is your responsibility to be aware of such changes and to review the policy each time you access and use our site. Minor changes to the policy may occur that will not affect our use of personal information. If our privacy policy changes in a way that we reasonably believe significantly affects the way we handle personal information, we will not use the information we have previously gathered without obtaining consent from the appropriate individual. 

**Revision date:** This policy was last updated on April 20, 2001.
